<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tutorial on Recursive Heuristics</title>
    <link>https://blog.okello.io/tags/tutorial/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tutorial on Recursive Heuristics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 13:21:34 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.okello.io/tags/tutorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Different Way to Think About Recursion</title>
      <link>https://blog.okello.io/tutorials/a-different-way-to-think-about-recursion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 13:21:34 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.okello.io/tutorials/a-different-way-to-think-about-recursion/</guid>
      <description>In order to understand recursion you must first understand recursion
If you are in a hurry, you can skip directly to the summary section.
Recursion is a simple but very confusing concept. When I first learned about it, I was confused as to how a function can call itself. I was working on some code the other day, and I had to use recursion to solve a problem, and while I was writing the function, I had a realization that changed how I look at recursion.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Recursively Convert Django Model to Dict</title>
      <link>https://blog.okello.io/tutorials/recursively-convert-django-model-to-dict/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 16:15:35 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.okello.io/tutorials/recursively-convert-django-model-to-dict/</guid>
      <description>In this article we will look at how to create your own recursive serializer in Django without using the Django Rest Framework Sometimes when working with Django, we may have some data that we want to serialize (convert to JSON) but we do not have the option of using the serializers that come with Django Rest Framework. The data can also take the same form for many cases and writing a new serializer for all of those cases can be tedious and repetitive.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Create Custom Permission Class in Django</title>
      <link>https://blog.okello.io/tutorials/create-custom-permission-class-in-django/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 15:36:25 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.okello.io/tutorials/create-custom-permission-class-in-django/</guid>
      <description>Permissions can be a hustle to deal with when developing an api. Suppose we have a number of api views and endpoints where the access permissions are very similar to one another with only slight variations..
We could create different permission classes with the slight changes that fit the specific endpoint&amp;rsquo;s needs. That works, but that involves a lot of repetition and duplicated code that can be hard to update later down the line.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
